Connection between PFSS and Process Yield
Welcome back to our session on Processing for Six Sigma.
Recall, that we looked at a little process consisting of three steps, three operations.
Operation 1, 2, 3. Also recall, that each of these operations
created a deliverable.
That the input coming into operation 1 adds value to what came in
and puts it out with higher value.
So, from a graphical point of view. If this is the scale of value,
our value steadily increases as we move through the process.
Okay. Now, here's something interesting.
We said that each operation has certain X’s.
X1, X2, through XN.
And that these X’s if you will, are what we call
critical to process variables. These are my CTP’s.
The ones that are among the vital few
are critical to the quality of the deliverable.
The trivial many down here. The X’s that are among the trivial many, are not CTP’s
because they're not critical to process operation.
They may be essential to process operation. But they're not critical to process operation.
In other words, how much light in the room
has little to do, but it is essential to see your work.
The process might be able to operate in the dark. See, it’s is not critical to process.
That's important to understand.
That the vital few X’s
are the critical to process variables.
Now, we have to also recognize that every one of these
critical to process variables has on its scale of measure.
A standard, like an upper spec limit and a lower spec limit
and a target value that's optimal.
In other words, this target value right here, is the optimal setting
for that vital few variable, for that critical to process variable.
Now, if all of the critical to process variables are at their optimal setting,
then the yield from this operation will be high.
So, there is a direct correlation to the goodness of the settings of the vital few variables.
The critical to process variables and the operations metric called yield.
Now, if this yield. And, I'm going to blow this up a little bit.
To where we've got operation 1, flowing into operation 2.
You see, if this yield right here and this yield.
Let's say that this is 90% and that that's 80%,
then the throughput yield, or the probability of going for both operations defect free
is .90 times .80 or .72 or 72%.
That’s to say there's a 72% probably of going through here defect free.
Now, listen to this. I’m going to give it to you real quick. This is important.
If I find the vital few, the critical to process variables, at operation 1
and I find their optimal setting. Their most advantageous setting.
And I set those variables there. Then this yield is going to increase.
This yield is going to go from like 90% to maybe 99.
If I do it at this operation as well. The yield might go from 80% to 90.
So, the net effect is .99 times .90 is approximately .90.
Compared to 72, which mean there's been about an 18% improvement in yield
from this operation.
Now, as that yield improves from that process.
See, there's that process right there, three operations.
Process A and I have process B, and I have process C that come together,
to blend into yet another process and that yield goes up.
Then the yield of the whole factory goes up. Which means the profits go up.
And that's the connectivity that we’re looking for and how it relates back
to process capability.
Thank you for choosing SSMI